[AWAKEN]
[Episode 13]
It's very sweet.
I'll save this honey for you.
You can have as much as you want
after your mission.
My time recovering here
has been like
five years ago
in Hangzhou.
From now on, in Hangzhou,
you are my husband, Sun Cheng,
and I am Mrs. Sun.
What is Mr. Sun like in his daily life?
For example,
Li Qing has a huge sweet tooth.
Honey and sugar-roasted chestnuts
are her absolute favorites,
but she rarely gets to have them.
Sun Cheng
likes to drink.
Drinking?
I can learn.
It's fine.
You can just drink soup.
Uncle Hai will take you there.
See you next time.
Will we see each other again?
Of course.
You told me
drinking soup is living a life,
and drinking alcohol
is having something on your mind.
But I really miss those days
of drinking soup.
Me too.
Come on, look at the camera.
Look this way.
A little closer.
As a married couple should be.
Right, come on.
Three, two, one.
Liu Xia.
Why are you standing here?
Take your medicine.
Water.
Go back to your ward,
or you might catch a cold.
Zhou Xue, won't you come out
for some exercise?
Go ahead.
Come on, Liu Xia.
Keep up.
Come on.
You got one. Well done.
You got one.
Keep it up, Liu Xia.
Next.
Come on, keep up.
You got one too?
Well done. Slow down.
Come on.
Next. Everyone gets a turn.
Time to eat.
What is it?
A math problem?
What's your name?
Know how to solve it?
Are you Mr. Ishida?
I'm from No. 76.
Mr. Kagesa invites you over.
Mr. Kagesa is looking for me?
Yes.
Who are you?
Mr. Ishida,
don't be afraid.
All you need to do is cooperate
and answer a few questions.
I don't understand.
I know your Chinese is very good.
Cooperating with me is your only way out.
Where is Ms. Ou Yang?
I don't know.
Do you remember now?
Mr. Ishida,
you should know what's good for you.
I know you want to go back to Japan.
As long as you tell me where Ou Yang is,
I can make the call right now
and let you go back.
But if you keep on like this,
I can only send you to Chongqing.
Over there,
I won't be the one calling the shots.
Just kill me.
You said he's a coward.
He's very stubborn.
I think
we should just send him to Chongqing.
Say something.
If we keep dawdling like this,
the Japanese will find out
sooner or later.
Let me think about it.
What are you doing?
Do me a favor.
I don't want to get married right now.
We'll talk about that later.
You'll go see someone now.
Who?
It's too lonely being alone.
Here's someone to keep you company.
Mr. Ishida.
Did they send you to get close to me
to find out about Ou Yang?
I'm not a member of the NBIS.
I just want you to live.
I won't believe you anymore.
I tried. Didn't work.
You beat him up like that.
How is that any different from No. 76?
To achieve our goal,
we use certain means.
Is there a problem?
Besides,
he's Japanese.
I can beat him up.
Cut the crap and make him talk.
You beat him up like that
and he didn't talk.
How am I supposed to get him to talk?
Then your friend will have to die.
I heard the Japanese like to
commit seppuku.
In a moment, I'm going to use this knife
to cut his belly open.
I'm going to see
if the Japanese really have
black intestines.
Then go ahead and cut mine open too.
You think I wouldn't dare?
Take a break from the violence.
You're not just helping me.
You're helping him too.
He doesn't trust me anymore.
He won't tell me.
You're a smart man,
and you know him well.
You'll find a way to make him talk.
I can't think of any.
Why do I feel like
you don't really want him to talk?
I really have no idea how to.
Just let me go.
For a Japanese,
is it worth it?
Are you going to kill me?
I can kill him.
I told them
to give you one more night
to save your life for now.
Involving irrelevant people
in our important project
is against the rules.
Captain Tao,
what do you mean?
I'm not sure if this Chen guy
is really working for us.
Do you have a better idea?
Anyway, if he doesn't cooperate,
I'll kill him.
Fine.
Then I'll kill you.
Ishida didn't return to Japan.
How much does he know
about Project Slumber?
He was one of the original members
of Project Slumber.
He is very important to our research work.
I will find him.
I sent someone to ask the person
in charge of the ship.
He didn't board the ship at all.
So Mr. Ishida hasn't left Shanghai?
We've searched the lab and his place.
There's no sign that he's been back.
There're only two possible reasons why
Mr. Ishida changed his itinerary
at the last minute.
Either he defected,
or he was kidnapped.
He wouldn't defect. It's a kidnapping.
Judging from the way it's done,
it should be the work of
the Hurricane Team.
I remember not long ago,
Director Li and Captain Du
had already wiped out the Hurricane Team,
and I requested commendation for you.
Looks like
there were some
that slipped through the net.
Please rest assured, General,
I will definitely find Ishida.
Alive? Or dead?
Find him,
dead or alive.
Be quick and give the Japanese something.
Make that woman shut her mouth.
Rest assured, Director.
If it really is the Hurricane Team,
I know how to find him.
According to Plum Blossom Agency,
before Ishida left,
he went to Fumin Hospital
to see an old friend.
An old friend?
Ou Yang.
Hoshino's former secretary.
She later went insane.
The Plum Blossom Agency
was worried she'd leak secrets,
so they temporarily put her
in the psychiatric ward.
Got it. I'll look into it right away.
The Propaganda Section said
Chen Kailai hasn't come to work today.
Ishida suddenly got kidnapped.
Chen Kailai hasn't come to work.
This is definitely no coincidence.
Could it be that they caught
Chen Kailai as well?
Have someone keep an eye out.
Let me know immediately
when Chen Kailai comes back.
Yes.
You seem to like snow very much.
Is it because your name is Zhou Xue,
and it has the word "snow" in it?
My name is Liu Xia.
Liu Xia (homophone of "stay").
You only stay in the hospital
if your illness can't be cured.
This name is unlucky.
So my name is not Liu Xia.
And your name is not Zhou Xue.
Your name is Ou Yang.
Then what is your name?
My name is Musheng.
Musheng,
hope this letter finds you well.
I came across your photos
and really liked them.
I, too, wanted to be like you,
going to the battlefield to do my part
and make a difference.
But it's no longer possible.
I have to leave China with my family.
Hello, Ou Yang.
Thank you for liking my photos.
I heard the cherry blossoms
in Japan are beautiful,
but I haven't seen them with my own eyes.
Musheng, hope this letter finds you well.
I really miss everything in China.
Your photos
are my only comfort in Japan.
Who are you, exactly?
You can hear me out first
and then decide if you want to go on.
I told you,
Musheng sent me.
It's just around the corner.
He showed you the letters I wrote?
Twenty-six letters in total.
"Musheng, hope this letter
finds you well."
This sentence,
you wrote it twenty-six times in total.
He copied every single letter of yours
into his notebook.
Musheng never gave up on you.
He sent me to save you.
Zhou Xue, are you asleep?
I'm coming in, okay?
Zhou Xue.
This is Mr. Du.
Don't take me away.
He's not taking you away or arresting you.
Mr. Du just wants to ask you
a few questions.
He'll leave after that.
May I ask
if you know where Ishida is?
Ishida?
I don't know him.
He's Dr. Hoshino's student.
Hoshino?
Hoshino can read minds.
He knows what you're thinking.
Hoshino stole my brain.
I'm not talking about Hoshino.
It's Ishida.
Right, Ishida.
Hoshino sent you to catch me?
Don't take me away!
-Okay. Okay.
-Don't take me away!
Okay, okay, he won't.
I told you.
She can't help you.
Please, Mr. Du.
So this is Musheng.
You mentioned in your letter
that you wanted a photo of him.
The negative of the photo
was kept in his notebook.
I think
it might have been for you.
Good thing he didn't send it to me.
Before I could go to Hangzhou to see him,
the Japanese came.
A few letters were not destroyed in time
and fell into the hands of the Japanese.
So I couldn't trust you at first.
Let's formally introduce ourselves.
I am "Su Causeway,"
Musheng's friend.
You are "Su Causeway."
Then what about him?
"Broken Bridge."
He once mentioned,
his name was given by his mother.
He lacked wood in the Five Elements,
so he was named Musheng.
"Broken Bridge"...
The character for "bridge"
also has "wood" in it.
But why did you come
instead of him?
He's dead.
Is he?
She used to be Hoshino's assistant too.
Later she went insane
and the Japanese locked her up here.
She probably knows some secrets.
I remember the female Communist
we caught before
was also looking for her.
Now that you mention it, I remember.
It's true.
Boss,
have the Communists gotten involved too?
Kidnapping Ishida doesn't seem like
something the Communists would do.
But we have to be on guard.
Send a few men
to keep an eye on Fumin Hospital.
Understood.
Have some water.
Thank you.
In Japan,
I was researching vaccine production
with Hoshino.
But later I found out
the purpose of that research
was not that simple.
I'm sorry.
Be careful.
Sorry.
I could tell from years of lab experience
that those were not animal test data.
The numbers on it
were all obtained through
human experiments.
They were data from in vivo experiments
on Chinese people.
Musheng gave me some information.
The plagues that broke out
in several places in China
also confirmed my guess.
But I was too scared.
I was an accomplice.
I would never be able to
atone for my sins.
The letters Musheng wrote
saved me.
He strengthened my resolve
to return to China.
Ou Yang,
hope this letter finds you well.
I can feel the hardships
you're going through in Japan,
as well as your helplessness
and frustration.
Because I am just as powerless as you.
Our country
is the same.
There is no hope in sight.
Shanghai has fallen,
followed by Nanjing and Hangzhou.
I am a photographer.
The camera is my gun.
In times of national crisis,
no matter who we are
or what we have done,
we should all do our part
to save the country.
Even if our contribution
may seem very small,
it is still a great one.
I want to do something.
I know I must do something.
I want to save this country
from its suffering in my own way.
I also know why you came to see me.
You want to learn about Hoshino's research
through me, right?
The research is nearing its end.
We too suspect
that this is a large-scale
biological attack
targeting Chinese people.
I hope you can help us
stop this project.
The work he didn't finish,
I will finish it for him.
Before I die,
I probably won't have the chance
to see her again.
If she is found,
there will be.
They promised me
that as long as they find Ou Yang,
they won't kill you.
But she's already gone mad.
It was all my fault.
Did you see her in China?
She rejected me.
Listen.
Our country gave her
the most advanced education,
yet she is not loyal to us.
This kind of woman is not worthy of you.
Do you think she will betray us?
She met a pen pal.
I think
she might betray us.
I ruined her.
I deserve to die for my sin.
I've had my last meal.
Let them do it as soon as possible.
I'll have a chat with Mr. Ishida.
Out you go.
Mr. Ishida,
those who die with sins
cannot go to heaven.
Now is your chance to atone.
I think her illness
is mostly psychological.
She will never get better here.
Tell us where Ou Yang is,
and we will take her to Chongqing.
She will get proper treatment
and may even recover.
Of course,
you will also be able to live.
Otherwise,
I will have to take you to Chongqing.
A lose-lose situation—
why go for that?
Mr. Ishida, you probably don't want
to be separated from your family
forever, right?
Will you cure her?
I never make promises lightly.
Fumin Hospital,
Psychiatric Ward,
Room 203.
Du Huangqiao has already
been to Fumin Hospital.
He is already wary of Ou Yang
and left secret sentries from No. 76
at the door.
We need to act as soon as possible.
Let him go back to Japan.
I only promised you
to spare his life for now.
Can I go home now?
When are you coming back?
What should I say if people ask about you?
I will go back
when things are done here.
You mind your own business.
If I wanted to betray you,
I'd have had plenty of chances.
I wouldn't have waited until now.
You know,
it's no use if I'm the only one
who trusts you.
Take me home!
He knows the rules pretty well.
What should we do with Ishida?
Chen Kailai wants me to spare his life.
Are you really going to do as he says?
If we let the Japanese go,
wouldn't that sell us all out?
Sparing his life doesn't mean
letting him go.
If Ou Yang gets rescued,
we'll send them both to Chongqing.
If she isn't rescued,
we'll hand him over to Chongqing
to fulfill our obligation.
Whatever Chongqing decides to do with him
is none of my business.
And I will have kept my promise
to Chen Kailai.
If you really value him that much,
you should recruit him.
I've said it before.
He's not like us.
How is he different?
He's a photographer.
An artist?
Affection can kill anyone.
"God of Wealth,"
don't ever let a man
get the better of you.
Where are you going?
To get breakfast.
Breakfast is ready for you.
Now that you're back, don't leave.
Why?
Ms. Jin ordered
that you rest well.
If you run around,
I'll lose my job.
How much is Jinbao paying you?
I'll pay you double.
Sir,
it's not about the money.
Ms. Jin will kill me.
Okay, I got it.
Chen Kailai is back at the photo studio.
He said he's sick
and needs a few days off.
Should I go fetch him?
No need.
He won't tell the truth anyway.
The phone is disconnected.
Ms. Jin asked to disconnect it
for a few days.
Who are you calling?
I need to call a customer
to let him know
his expedited photos are ready.
If you disconnect the phone,
how am I supposed to notify him?
Are we still running a business?
I haven't seen any customers
these past few days.
Just because you don't have customers
doesn't mean I don't.
Mr. Zhao.
Mr. Chen, how's business lately?
We're still counting on friends like you
to keep us going.
By the way,
I was just about to come find you.
Well...
Meng's photos are ready.
Thanks for rushing them out.
I heard you got sick.
How are you feeling?
Just a bit of insomnia and a headache.
Nothing serious.
Captain Du came to see me.
It seems everyone cares about you.
Inspector Su is worried too.
I know.
Tell Inspector Su
I'll be able to go to work soon.
Right, Xin Xiang?
Yes.
Mr. Chen will recover very soon.
Okay, let's meet up when you recover.
Okay, take care.
NBIS has located Ou Yang
at Fumin Hospital.
Who are you?
Liu Xia's family member.
Liu Xia, your father is here to see you.
How are you feeling, hon?
I'm doing well.
I'm ready to be discharged.
I'll leave you to it.
Uncle Hai.
Ou Yang has agreed to cooperate
and leave with us.
We can leave at any time.
But did you notice
that the guards at the stairs
have been changed?
Du Huangqiao came last night.
The guards were changed this morning.
They must be his secret sentries.
Looks like NBIS has zeroed in
on this place.
They act fast
and could snatch Ou Yang at any moment.
This adds
another layer of uncertainty for us.
Then what should we do?
"Diana" has made a new plan.
We'll wait for the NBIS to make their move
before we do.